# YOUSIF A. SALAME

Abu Dhabi, UAE +971 50 471 5875

salamey3@gmail.com | www.yousifsalame.com

Nationality: Lebanese | DOB: March 13, 1982 | Marital Status: Married

Languages: Arabic (native), English (Professional)

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts (2011)
Electronic Media and Broadcasting, Major
Communication Studies, Minor
Northern Kentucky University, Highland Heights, KY, USA

### CAREER SUMMARY

#### Director • Editor • Producer • Online Video Content Creator

- Creative and transformative Content Creator with 14 years of experience providing digital
  content that hits the target within the anticipated deadline and meticulous project execution.
- A "best of both worlds" Director & Editor with deep technical and creative expertise across
  digital platforms and broadcast networks, with an ability to devise and execute integrated
  campaigns that engage audiences and deliver strong ROI.
- A technically inclined superior expertise in live streaming with engineer-like understanding of
  live streaming and broadcast systems such as Blackmagic Design ATEM devices, Vision Mixer,
  and V-Mix with hundreds of live shows done with flawless precision and client satisfaction.

### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Copy Writing / Editing
- Video Directing & Editing
- Camera operating
- Video production
- Customer-oriented skills
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe After Effects

- Avid Media Composer
- Final Cut Pro
- DaVinci Resolve Studio
- Live streaming
- Vision mixer, ATEM Blackmagic, V-Mix
- Open Broadcaster Software | OBS

- Online Content Creator
- Brand Awareness
   Campaigns
- Cross-Functional Team Leadership
- Wordpress
- SEO
- Content Strategy

Please connect with me on:

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### The Real Estate Report, Dubai, UAE

(Freelance Project-based) May 2023 - July 2023

#### **Media Consultant & Director**

Directing the Real Estate Report show which hosts industry experts, targeting real estate investors looking for the latest data and insights into the market.

- Directing and Editing the full episodes of the show
- Publishing the episodes to YouTube, iTunes, Anghami, and Spotify
- Creating short form content out of the full episode to publish to social media

Media Avenue, Dubai, UAE - Paris, France

(Project-based) Jan 2023 – July 2023

#### **Creative Director**

Develop and implement marketing campaign and material for luxury products (Watches, Handbags, and Jewelry) for several clients and high end brands such as ((Rolex, Omega, Tudor, Breitling, Burberry, Yves Saint Laurent, Louis Vuiton, Prada, and Chanel)

- *Ideation and conceptualization* of the marketing campaign
- Implementation of campaign material from photography, videography, and editing
- Publishing and management of the campaign with PPC, SEO, affiliates, and influencers

#### Oldtimer Middle East, Dubai, UAE

May 2022 - May 2023

## **Digital Marketing Manager**

Visual transformation for the company's online presence with all its products and services

- **Develop and implement an online strategy** by researching competitors, determining suitable platforms, evaluating performance, crafting messages, and identifying target audiences.
- **Produce, modify, publish, and distribute** daily content (including text, images, and videos) that fosters meaningful connections and motivates community members to engage.
- **Establish and optimize company pages** on various platforms to enhance the visibility of the company's social content, and create schedules for content publication and distribution.

#### Eagle Films, Abu Dhabi, UAE

(Freelance Project-based) January 2022 – April 2022

#### **Series Video Editor**

With a team of 3 editors supervised by the head of the editing department

- **Synchronizing and cleaning everyday's shoots** using Adobe Premiere as the editing software to sync all the footage to their audio using time-code sync.
- Assembling episodes meeting the writer's and director's visions.
- Finalizing episodes and sharing with Shahid upon receiving form the preceding departments.

Please connect with me on:

## Co-Founder, Director, and Head of Editing Department

With my 3 partners and a small investment of \$25K, I co-founded Fine Line Production in 2017

- Procuring more than 20 clients representing big names who also gave referrals to other clients with great track record in customer satisfaction and goal-oriented end product.
- Growing the team from the initial 4 investors to a team of 20 experts growth in company assets and value by more than 500% from the initial investment.
- Devising strategic campaign plans for the clients enhancing their visibility across social media
  platforms, with business-oriented blogs and video content that made them prominently present on top
  of the search engines search results.

### Future Television, Beirut, LEBANON

October 2012 - February 2015

### **Assistant Producer, and Segment Director**

- **Coordinating major stories for the newscast** between producers, reporters, and the execution of the love newscast in the control room.
- **Producing segments for Paula Yaakoubian's show titled "Interviews"** and assisted in the execution of the live remote show from the OB Van.
- **Producing segments for the daily show "Akhbar al Sabah"** and assisted in the execution of the live remote show from the studio and control room.

### **<u>Lebanese American University (LAU)</u>**, Beirut, LEBANON

January 2012 – February 2015

#### Studio Administrator, Workshops Coordinator

- Conducting regular workshops in camera operating, light design, sound design, and video editing supporting material for class curriculum.
- Managing classes and theater and studio venues making sure they are well equipped and ready for the following classes or assignments given to students.